Jeremy Moseley

Full Stack Engineer

- **♀** Jeremy Moseley 14018 25th Ave NE Seattle, WA 98125, 98107, Seattle (US), WA
- ✓ jeremy.moseley@gmail.com
- **L** 1-415-926-1955
- n jmoseley in Jeremy Moseley

About

Jeremy is a focused engineer who is intrigued by the design and architecture of distributed systems. He has experience with distributed systems in Scala, Python, and Typescript/Javascript, and has dabbled in everything from HTML to databases and operating systems.

Experience

Convoy

November 2016 - Present

Software Engineer

https://www.convoy.com

Small agile team working to disrupt the freight industry using product driven development. Engineering work focusses on mobile and web apps built around a microservice architecture using cutting edge technology like React and Node.

Mentoring more junior engineers at various stages of their careers (non-traditional background & first job, lightly experienced & starting to tackle larger scope, and traditional background & somewhat experienced).

Working on projects with Org wide scope, evangelizing and pushing on solutions to large technical project with organizational scope and a large breadth of stakeholders.

Led the team to developed the first version of a system wide stress testing plan, used to ensure that our systems can handle extreme near-term growth.

Learned Javascript and Node quickly become a productive member of the team, working closely with Product to develop useful features for both internal and external users. Maintain and external systems that allow complex integrations with external customer systems.

Technology: Typescript/Javascript, PostgreSQL, AWS, React

Inkling Systems Inc.

June 2015 - November 2016

Import/Export Software Engineer 3

https://www.inkling.com

The Import/Export squad manages all methods for bring content into and out of the Inkling platform, providing infrastructure for converting content from Word to HTML, HTML to EPUB and PDF, as well as conversion to internal formats for Inkling's internal readers.

Reduced content export errors by 10%, increasing customer satisfaction and reducing customer support overhead.

Architected a new microservice using the Play framework and an SQS task processor to provide a scalable worker system to allow easy scaling for demand

Developed a successful Seattle intern program

Technology: Scala, Java, Play, AWS, SQS, PostgreSQL, Python, XML

Inkling Systems Inc.

June 2014 - June 2015

Infrastructure Engineer

https://www.inkling.com

The infrastructure team manages infrastructure tooling and AWS deployment of the Inkling stack. Supports other engineering teams to make deployment and infrastructure management more reliable and easier to work with.

Implemented a state-of-the-art distributed log systems that handles 30 million events a day.

Migrated Inkling's deployment and packaging system to Docker

Significantly reduced downtime caused by deployments

Increasing engineering efficiency when developing and deploying new services

Operated as a member of the emergency on-call rotation

Technology: Scala, AWS, Python, Bash, PostgreSQL, Docker

Inkling Systems Inc.

September 2013 - December 2013

Platform Engineering Intern

https://www.inkling.com

Developed and deployed an XML database, and developed supporting features in the core Python API

Wrote complex XQuery scripts and API interfaces

Technology: BaseX, XPath, XQuery, XML, Python

Internet Shakespeare Editions

October 2012 - August 2013

Part-time Developer

http://ise.uvic.ca

Part-time member of a team while in studying, using XQuery and XPath to maintain and develop new features for a long-term academic project. Designed a mobile experience, as well as used XQuery and XPath to process and transform marked up content in a variety of interesting ways, depending on how the content was being consumed.

Designed a mobile-first experience from scratch

Wrote complex and performant XQuery scripts to transform marked up content on the fly for mobile consumption

Technology: eXistDB, XPath, XQuery, XML, CSS, Javascript

Developed deep packet inspection (DPI) plugins for a software package that runs on network hardware.

Analyzed raw network traffic to extract patterns for various traffic types (HTTP, TCP, UDP, etc)

Designed code to analyze Facebook, Google, Steam, and a variety of other application streams

Technology: C++

Education

University of Victoria

2009 - 2014

Bachelor

Software Engineering

PA: 6.39

SAIT Polytechnic

2006 - 2007

Associates Degree

Computer Engineering Technology

Intellij

PA: 3.9

Skills

Development Tools

Visual Studio Code



PyCharm

Languages/Frameworks



Sublime Text 2/3

Git

SBT

Database

API Design



Cloud



Languages

English

Interests

mountain biking technology technology technology user experience future